(走过的路)
你是谁
Who are you?
卡西迪奥  我是侍奉主的天使
Castiel. I'm an angel of the lord.
我体内流着恶魔的血液  迪恩
I've got demon blood in me,dean!
我整一个新等级的怪物
I'm a whole new level of freak!
莉莉丝正试图打破这66个封印
Lilith is trying to break the 66 seals
让路西法从地狱重获自由
To free lucifer from hell.
这就是天使将我拯救出地狱的原因吗
And why would an angel rescue me from hell?
因为我们有任务授予你
Because we have work for you.
她不是护士  而是莉莉丝的御用主厨
She's no nurse. she's lilith's personal chef.
喝恶魔的血  你从开始就应该知道这是错误的
Sucking blood? you got to know that's wrong.
我多希望自己可以收手
I wish to god I could stop.
你愿意完全交出自己
You give yourself over wholly
为上帝和天使们服务吗
To the service of god and his angels?
是的  我发誓
Yes. I swear.
你是天使  不是吗  我是撒迦利亚
You're an angel,aren't you? I'm zachariah.
这个人是上帝的先知
This man is a prophet of the lord.
我不是为了追求刺激才去喝恶魔的血
I'm not drinking the demon blood for kicks.
她是毒药  萨姆
She's poison,sam!
看看她都对你做了什么
Look what she did to you!
你要是走出这扇门  就永远别回来了
You walk out that door,don't you ever come back.
Don't you cry no more
圣玛丽女修道院
伊尔切斯特  马里兰州
1972年
天哪  不
Oh,my god! no!
我们在天上的父
Our father who art in...Heaven...
愿人尊父的名为圣
Hallowed be thy name.
愿父的国降临  等等  等等
Thy kingdom come,blah,blah,blah.
带领我们远离诱惑
Lead us not into temptation,
救我们脱离邪恶
But deliver us...from evil.
深表赞同  修女们
Truer words never spoken,huh,sisters?
但是有时候
But sometimes it seems
很难理解造物者
As if it's difficult to know the creator.
有时候我觉得特别是执着于字面意思
Sometimes I feel -- in a very literal sense --
就常会在追寻上帝的道路里
That I have been wandering the desert for years
迷失多年
Looking for our father.
好吧  不是我们的天父
Well,not our father.
而是我的天父
My father.
看  他还在监狱
See,he's in jail.
你们的天父将他囚禁在那里
Your dad put him there.
我几乎放弃希望
I almost gave up hope.
但俗话说"要留有一点信仰"
But "ye of little faith"...
让我最终找到了他
Because I finally found him --
至少  打开他牢门的地方
Or at least,you know,the spot where his cage door opens.
正好在这里
It's right here...
老天啊  居然在这么个不起眼的修道院里
In a damn convent,for god's sake.
生活真有趣
Life is funny.
神父
Uh...father?
闭上你们的臭嘴  你这小荡妇
Shut your friggin' pie hole,you little slut!
而且我觉得这么安排还是有道理的
Then again,I suppose it makes sense.
人们或许忘了
Folks forget --
毕竟我父亲也是一个天使
My daddy is an angel,after all.
或者说曾经是
Or was.
假设有些蠢蛋站在这儿
I mean,I suppose some dumb bastard stood here,
流着他那虔诚的眼泪  寻思到
Felt a jolt of his holy juice,and thought,
我要为自己修建一所修道院
"i'm gonna build me a nun factory."
好吧
Well...
这个想法不错
It's the right idea...
罪恶的天使
Wrong angel.
因此
So,um...
如果你们中有人要祷告的话
If any of you gals are the praying type,
现在可以开始了
Now would be a good time to start.
[邪恶力量 第4季第22集]
路西法复苏
萨姆
Sam?
神晃去哪里啦
Your head in the game,here?
我很好  我们走吧
I'm good. let's go.
你还好吗
You okay?
我刚说了我很好
I just said I was.
听着  我知道这不关我事
Look,I know hand-holding really isn't my thing...
但至少迪恩对你的抨击是不对的
But still,dean was wrong saying what he said to you.
不  他有权说那些
No,he was right to say it.
我不怪他  毕竟是我不对
I mean,I don't blame him,after what I did.
好吧  等我们了结这事后  你们会和好如初的
Well,after we're done,you guys will patch things up.
你们总是分分合合
I mean,you always do.
你说的好像我曾有过将来
You're talking like I got an "after."
不要这么说
Don't say that.
露比  我能感觉到他在我体内
I can feel it inside me,ruby.
我已经变了
I've changed --
永远的
For good.
现在再也不能回头了
There's no going back now.
萨姆
Sam --
听着  我知道自己应该做什么
Look... I know what I got to do.
那没什么大不了
It's okay.
我只是想说
I'm just saying.
迪恩还是离我越远越好
Dean's better off as far away from me as possible.
不管怎么样  都不重要了
Anyway,doesn't matter.
我们去摆平这一切吧
Let's just get this done with.
迪恩
Dean?
Dean.
你有在听我说话吗
You listen to a word I said?
我在听
Yeah,I heard you.
我不会给他打电话的
I'm not calling him.
别逼我动枪  臭小子
Don't make me get my gun,boy.
世界末日正邪交锋在即
We are damn near kickoff for armageddon.
你不认为我们有更重要的任务吗
Don't you think we got bigger fish at the moment?
我知道你气坏了
I know you're pissed,
我也不是在替他的所作所为道歉
And I'm not making apologies for what he's done,
但是他和你有血缘关系吗
But he's your... blood?
他和我有血缘关系  这是不是就是你要说的？
He's my blood -- is that what you're gonna say?
他是你亲弟弟  而且他堕落了
He's your brother,and he's drowning.
鲍比  我试图帮助他  我真的尽力了
Bobby,I tried to help him. I did.
看看都发生了什么
Look what happened.
那就再试一次
So try again.
一切都太迟了
It's too late.
没有的事
There's no such thing.
才不呢  见鬼
No! Damn it!
不
No.
我们得面对现实
We got to face the facts --
萨姆从来就不想成为这个家的一员
Sam never wanted part of this family.
他讨厌在这种生活状态下成长
He hated this life growing up --
他得到第一次机会就是远赴斯坦福
Ran away to Stanford first chance he got.
现在就像是超时空效应历史再次重演
And now it's like da ja vu all over again.
我已经厌倦追在他屁股后面跑了
Well,I am sick and tired of chasing him.
滚他的吧  他可以随心所欲了
Screw him. He can do what he wants.
- 你不是那个意思  - 不  鲍比  我就是那个意思
-You don't mean that. -Yes,I do,bobby.
萨姆走了
Sam's gone.
他走了
He's gone.
我甚至都不确定他还是不是我弟弟
I'm not even sure if he's still my brother anymore.
虽然他曾经是
If he ever was.
你这个蠢蛋  超级大蠢蛋
You stupid,stupid son of a bitch!
好吧  哭去吧
Well,boohoo!
我很遗憾你的感情受挫了  我的小王子
I am so sorry your feelings are hurt,princess!
你是不是觉得
Are you under the impression
家人就应该要处处取悦你
that family's supposed to make you feel good --
也许还得给你烤个苹果派
Bake you an apple pie,maybe?
家人就是让你为之担忧的一群人
They're supposed to make you miserable!
所以你们才成了一家人
That's why they're family!
我和他说过了  "出了这个门  就别再回来"
I told him,"You walk out that door,don't come back,"
而他就那么走了
And he walked out anyway.
是他选择了这种结局
That was his choice!
你就像个满腹牢骚的小屁孩
You sound like a whiny brat.
不对
No.
你和你老爸一个口气
You sound like your dad.
好吧  让我来告诉你
Well,let me tell you something --
你爸爸就是个懦夫
Your dad was a coward.
我爸爸可能有很多恶习  但他绝不是懦夫  鲍比
My dad was a lot of things,Bobby,but a coward?
他宁愿把萨姆赶得远远地也不愿意接近他
He'd rather push sam away than reach out to him.
我可不认为那是勇敢的表现
Well,that don't strike me as brave.
你比任何时候的你老爸都要勇敢
You are a better man than your daddy ever was.
所以就当成全我们俩
So you do both of us a favor --
别学他
Don't be him.
你好  迪恩
Hello,Dean.
差不多是时候了
It's almost time.
我们该去育儿室了  小甜心
We're gonna take you to the nursery,sugar --
让妈妈爸爸休息一会儿吧
Let mommy and daddy get some sleep.
他真是个漂亮的小宝贝
He's a beautiful child.
绝对完美
Absolutely scrumptious.
你拍一  我拍一
patty-cake,patty-cake,baker's man
一个小孩穿花衣
bake me a cake as fast as you can
你拍二  我拍二
pat it and roll it and mark it with a "b"
两个小孩梳小辫
and put it in the oven --
我们得谈谈了
So,we need to talk.
你好  迪恩
Hello,Dean.
你看起来状态不错
You're looking fit.
好吧  听听这个怎么样
Well,how 'bout this?
小查和小卡的顶级生活
"The suite life of Zack and Cass."
那是个...
It's a --
当我没说
Never mind.
所以这算什么  我到底在哪里
So,what is this? where the hell am I?
应该叫它演员休息室
Call it a greenroom.
我们现在正接近最后的高潮
We're closing in on the grand finale,here.
我们希望在你闪亮登场之前保证你的安全
We want to keep you safe before showtime.
来个汉堡包吧  你的最爱
Try a burger. They're your favorite.
从特拉华州的海滨小屋来的
From that seaside shack in Delaware.
我记得你一次吃过11个
You were 11,I think.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
不饿吗
No?
"盖里甘的岛"第二季里的红发美女怎么样
How about ginger from season 2 of "Gilligan's island"?
你和她有一腿  是吧
You do have a thing for her,don't you?
有诱惑力
Tempting.
真奇怪
Weird.
我们可以免费让玛丽 安入伙
We'll throw in Mary Ann for free.
不  不行
No,no.
放弃全像甲板  好吗
Let's...bail on the holodeck,okay?
我想知道游戏计划是什么
I want to know what the game plan is.
我们担心下这事吧
Let us worry about that.
我们需要你  集中精力  放松心情
We want you... focused,relaxed.
那我有可能不爽然后离开的
Well,I'm about to be pissed and leaving,
所以现在说吧  你个二
So start talking,chuckles.
所有的封印都失效了
All the seals have fallen.
除了一个
Except one.
真是个令人称奇的记录  这很
That's an impressive score. That's...
真像是华府官员做出的事
That's right up there with the Washington generals.
你认为这是恰当的挖苦吗
You think sarcasm's appropriate,do you?
考虑到
Considering...
是你让所有事开始的
You started all this?
最后的封印
But the final seal...
是大不一样的
...it'll be different.
怎么说
Why?
莉莉丝会去打破它
Lilith has to break it.
她是唯一一个可以去的
She's the only one who can.
明晚  午夜时分
Tomorrow night -- midnight.
在哪里
Where?
-我们在努力找寻中  -好吧  努力点
- We're working on it.  - Well,work harder.
我们做我们的事  你只要做你自己的事
We'll do our job. You just make sure you do yours.
那个到底是什么玩意  确切点说
Yeah,and what is that,exactly?
如果我是阻止她的那个人  怎么做  用刀吗
If I'm supposed to be the one that stops her,how? with the knife?
-一切都在掌握之中  -现在是个好时机吗
- All in good time.  - Isn't now a good time?
-有点信心好吗  -什么  对你有信心吗
- Have faith.  - What,in you?
给个相信你的理由先
Give me one good reason why I should.
因为你发过誓你要效忠于我
Because you swore your obedience.
所以遵守命令
So obey.
什么  没有恶魔陷阱吗
What,no devil's trap?
我用不着
I don't need one.
看看你自己 是在班门弄斧吗
Look at you -- all 'rounded up.
就像是圣母玛利亚矗在那里
It's like a-rod and Madonna over here.
莉莉丝在哪
Where's Lilith?
我不是在吓你
I'm not scared of you.
实际上你是在吓我
Yeah,you are,actually.
好像还有很好的理由
And with good reason.
听着 什么是我的策略
Look... what's my upside?
我告诉你  你会杀了我
Okay,I tell you,you kill me.
我不告诉你  你还是要杀了我
I don't tell you,you still kill me.
就算我逃离了这里  莉莉丝最终还是会杀了我
I get away somehow,Lilith will definitely kill me.
那我的好处在哪
So where's my carrot?
我觉得你死之前用不着担心
I think what you should be worrying about
用不着担心会发生什么事
Is what happens before you die.
真糟糕
Ah,screw it.
我是萨姆  请留言
It's Sam. Leave me a message.
是我
Hey,it's m-me.
我只是刚好想起来
Look,I'll just get right to it.
我还是很不爽
I'm still pissed...
我还欠你一顿扁
And I owe you a serious beatdown.
但
But...
我不该说那些话
...I shouldn't have said what I said.
我不是爸爸
You know,I'm not dad.
我们是兄弟  我们是一家人
We're brothers. You know,we're family.
还有
And,uh...
无论事情变得多糟  这都不会改变的
No matter how bad it gets,that doesn't change.
萨姆  我很抱歉
Sammy,I'm sorry --
停下来  拜托了
Stop! Stop! Please!
你打算告诉我她在哪了吗
You'll tell me where she is?
好的  只是  让我死吧
Fine. Fine. Just...let me die.
成交
Deal.
明晚  午夜时分
Tomorrow night... midnight...
她会到修道院去
She's gonna be at a convent --
马里兰州  伊尔切斯特  名字是圣玛丽
St. Mary's,Ilchester,Maryland.
修道院吗
A convent?
莉莉丝
Lilith...
她会打破最后一个封印
She's gonna break the final seal.
最后一个封印是什么玩意
And what is the final seal?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不知道  不知道啊
Aaaah! I don't know! I don't know!
我发誓  我不知道
I don't know! I swear!
拜托了
Ohh,please!
我在乞求你  请杀了我吧
I'm begging you -- kill me,please!
好的
Fine.
等下
Wait.
不能杀
You can't.
为什么不
Why not?
因为我们要带上她
Because we got to take her with us.
这是最后的冲刺
It's the final run on the death star,
你需要更多恶魔的血
And you need more juice than I got.
你答应过的
You promised.
抱歉了  姐妹
Sorry,sister.
你走路说话就能轻易打败别人
You're a walking,talking can of whup-ass.
你这个贱人
You bitch!
我知道  如今没几个人能信得过
I know. Just can't trust anyone these days.
不过至少你不能轻易地把我杀死
Well,least you won't be able to crack me open that easy.
是吗
That so?
别忘了  让你流血的不只我一个
Don't forget,it's not just me you're bleeding.
其实  我也很想
In fact,I think I'm gonna take a little...
潜意识的小睡会
Siesta in the subconscious.
让身体也放松下
Hand over the wheel for a little bit.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
注册护士辛迪·麦凯琳
Cindy Mccellen,r.n.,
快回来吧
Come on down!
什么情况
What...
我在哪
Where am I?
天哪  我动不了
Oh,my god,I can't move.
发生了什么事
What's going on?
救命
Help!
请救救我
Help me,please.
算你狠
Great.
圣玛丽女修道院
伊尔切斯特  马里兰州 1972年
天父  你看
Father,look...
我不完全是祈祷的人
I'm not exactly the praying type,
但是我还是做出了牺牲
But still... I made the sacrifice.
我给你送来了那么多修女
I got you a bagful of nuns.
那么
So,uh...
你能听到我说话吗
Can you hear me?
你能通过门小声跟我说吗
Can you whisper through the door?
孩子  我在这里
I'm here,my son.
天父  听到你声音真是太好了
It's so good to hear your voice,padre.
我找你很久了
I have been searching for you for so long.
你不会了解
You have no idea.
其他人都失去了自己的信仰
The others have lost faith.
都是群异教徒
Dickless heathens.
但我不是
But not me.
你做得很好
You've done well.
那么
So,uh...
我如何救你出来
How do I bust you out?
莉莉丝
Lilith.
Lilith?
天父  她
Father,she's...
她被深深地困在下面
Trapped neck-deep in the pit.
这不好办啊
It won't be easy.
莉莉丝
Lilith.
莉莉丝可以打破封印
Lilith can break the seals.
好吧
Yeah,okay.
但是我要怎么做
But what do I do?
你必须给我找个孩子
You must find me a child.
一个很特别的孩子
A very special child.
什么意思
What do you mean?
什么孩子
What child?
你不是在开玩笑吧
You got to be kidding me.
圣玛丽的开膛手
圣玛丽的神父在将8名修女开膛破肚后...
什么
What?
找到了这个
Get this.
1972年  被遗弃的圣玛丽女修道院
St. Mary's,abandoned in '72
一个牧师挖出八个女修女的肠子后
After a priest disemboweled eight nuns.
血流成河  不堪入目
What's black and white and red all over?
这不好笑
That's not funny.
牧师说不是他的错
The priest said it wasn't his fault.
他声称是恶魔逼他做的
He said a demon made him do it.
他还记得那个恶魔的名字
And that he even remembered the demon's name.
是吗
Yeah?
阿撒兹勒
Azazel.
莉莉丝  黄眼恶魔
So,Lilith,yellow-eyes,
名单上的人都来了
All the a-listers are paying visits.
必然要走到一起
Certainly gives the joint credibility.
也正是最后一个封印被打破的地方
As a place where the final seal goes down.
对我来说已经够好了
Well,it's good enough for me.
把漂亮女护士带上  准备上路
Let's pack up nurse betty and hit the road.
或许  听着
Hey,maybe,um... look.
什么事
What?
或许我们能找到另一个恶魔
Maybe we can find another demon.
萨姆  不要
Sam,no.
那只是不要伤害我的谎话  是在演戏而已
That blubbery "don't hurt me" crap,it's just an act.
她在耍你
She's playing you.
我不是很肯定
I'm not so sure.
即使是真的  还有个睡着的恶魔在她体内
Even if she's not,there's still a hell-bitch snoozing in there.
算了吧
I mean,come on.
不像你以前的做事风格  对吧
It's not like you haven't done this before,right?
别这样  求求你们
No,please don't.
听我说  我叫辛迪·麦凯琳
Just,just listen to me,okay? My name is Cindy Mccellen.
埃菲尔德纪念医院新生儿重症监护室的护士
I'm a nurse in the NICU over at Enfield Memorial.
我的丈夫叫马修  知道吗
I have a husband named Matthew,okay?
我们结婚6年了
We've been married six years.
他一定担心死我了
He's got to be worried sick about me.
我连你是谁都不知道
And I don't even know who you are,
我也不会把事情说出去的
And I'm not gonna tell anybody anything.
求求你放了我吧
Please just let me go.
不要
No-o-o!
不  不
No! No!
求求你  不
Please,no!
求你了
Please...
救命
Help!
你是要见我吗
You asked to see me?
是的  我有所求
Yeah,listen,I,uh,I-I need something.
想要啥就说
Anything you wish.
我要你带我去见萨姆
I need you to take me to see Sam.
为什么
Why?
我有话要对他说
There's something I got to talk to him about.
说什么
What's that?
我今天早上说的  你觉得怎么样
The b.m. I took this morning. what's it to you?
要抓紧时间了
Just make it snappy.
我觉得这很不明智
I don't think that's wise.
我可没问你意见
Well,I didn't ask you for your opinion.
难道你忘了你们上次见面的经历了
Have you forgotten what happened the last time you met?
没有
No.
正因如此才要去见
That's the whole point.
听着  我会乖乖听你们的话的  行吗
Listen,I'm gonna do whatever you mooks want,okay?
我就这么一个要求
I just need to tie up this one thing.
五分钟就好
Five minutes -- that's all I need.
不行
No.
你说"不行"是什么意思
What do you mean,no?
我被软禁在这儿了
Are you saying that I'm trapped here?
你想去哪里都行
You can go wherever you want.
很好  我想见萨姆
Super. I want to go see sam.
除了见他
Except there.
-我想去散散心  -行啊  我陪你
- I want to take a walk.  - Fine. I'll go with you.
-我一个人去  -不行
- Alone.  - No.
别废他妈话了  我要出去
You know what? Screw this noise. I'm out of here.
从哪扇门出去
Through what door?
他娘的
Damn it.
一条来自迪恩的新语音留言
阅听
关闭
你又不是12岁小姑娘
What are you,a 12-year-old girl?
做都做了还纠结啥
Just play it already.
管好你自己的事
Mind your own business.
天啊  真希望她能闭上嘴
God,I wish she would just shut up.
这个你也能解决的
Well,that can be arranged.
我真不明白
I don't get it.
你用那把刀杀了那么多恶魔
All the demons you cut with the knife,
换成天使又如何
What do you think happens to the host?
会有什么不同
How is this any different?
你觉得这会让我感觉好过点吗
Is that supposed to make me feel better?
我知道你现在不好受  萨姆
I know that you're having a tough time here,Sam,
但我们已经快到终点了
But we're in the final lap here.
现在可不是娘娘腔的时候
Now is not the time to grow a persqueeter.
你就不能改改态度吗
Would you drop the friggin' attitude?
我就要去吸一个无辜的女人的血
I'm about to bleed and drink an innocent woman
而且还当着她的面
While she watches.
但这是为了拯救世界啊
And save the world as a result.
我不知道  我觉得
I don't know. I-I just...
我开始认为
I'm starting to think...
也许迪恩是对的
Maybe Dean was right.
哪些事
About what?
所有事
About everything.
我们会挺过去的  对吗  萨姆
We're gonna see this through,right,Sam?
萨姆
Sam?
他妈的混蛋
Son of a bitch.
别像只咆哮的猴子似的出口成脏  行不
Quit hurling feces like a howler monkey,would you?
这可不太合适
It's unbecoming.
让我出去
Let me out of here.
我告诉过你  外面很危险
Like I told you... too dangerous out there.
恶魔们到处徘徊
Demons on the prowl.
我一直都生活在危险之中
I've been getting my ass kicked all year.
你现在倒开始为我的安全着想了
Now you're sweating my safety?
你在撒谎
You're lying.
我要见我弟弟
I want to see my brother.
这个  太欠考虑
That's...ill-advised.
我相当讨厌你废话连篇
You know,I am so sick of your crap riddles
而且自以为是  大饼脸
And your smug,fat face.
到底是怎么回事
What the hell is going on,huh?
为什么我不能见萨姆
Why can't I see Sam?
我要怎么去除掉莉莉丝
And how am I gonna ice Lilith?
你不用
You're not.
去除掉莉莉丝
...going to ice lilith.
什么
What?
莉莉丝要打破最后一个封印了
Lilith's going to break the final seal.
这已是既成事实
Fait accompli at this point.
火车已经离站
Train's left the station.
但是我和萨姆  我们可以阻止
But me and Sam,we can stop...
你们不想阻止天启  是不
You don't want to stop it,do you?
说对了
Nope.
从没想过
Never did.
末日近了
The end is nigh.
天启即将降临  孩子  就在附近一家剧院
The apocalypse is coming,kiddo,to a theater near you.
那还保护封印干嘛
What was all that crap about saving seals?
那只是障眼法
Our grunts on the ground...
不能公开全部真相
We couldn't just tell them the whole truth.
不然你们还不全反了
We'd have a full-scale rebellion on our hands.
想想看
I mean,think about it...
如果不是上面有人乐见其成
Would we really let 65 seals get broken
我们怎么会让他们轻易解开65道封印
Unless senior management wanted it that way?
为什么
But why?
为什么不呢
Why not?
天启
The apocalypse.
名字吓人  营销失败  人人避之不及
Poor name,bad marketing... puts people off.
其实只不过是场大规模的
When all it is is Ali-Foreman...
拳王争霸赛
On a... slightly larger scale.
我们胜券在握
And we like our chances.
我们获胜之后  那是一定的
When our side wins -- and we will...
人间就是天堂
It's paradise on earth.
有什么不好的
Now,what's not to like about that?
那人类怎么办
What happens to all the people
怎么承受你们的怒火之战
During your little pissing contest?
舍不得孩子套不着狼
You can't make an omelet without cracking a few eggs.
这次舍的多了些而已
In this case... truckloads of eggs,
总之你明白咯
But you get the picture.
听着
Look...
没什么大不了的
It happens.
我们不是第一次清理地球了
This isn't the first planetary enema we've delivered.
醒醒吧  迪恩
Uh,no,Dean.
甭拿那玩意敲我的脑袋
Probably shouldn't try to bash my skull in with that thing.
你不会喜欢结果的
Wouldn't end up too pleasant for you.
那萨姆呢
What about Sam?
他不会坐以待毙  他会阻止莉莉丝
He won't go quietly. He'll stop Lilith.
萨姆是计划的一部分
Sam... has a part to play.
很重要的部分
A very important part.
他可能需要些指导
He may need a little nudging in the right direction,
我会保证他听话的
But I'll make sure he plays it.
什么意思
What does that mean?
你要把他怎么样
What are you gonna do to him?
萨姆  萨姆 老是萨姆
Sam,Sam,Sam. Marcia,Marcia,Marcia.
能不能忘了他
Forget about him,would you?
你有大事要做
You have larger concerns.
你以为我干嘛要告诉你真相
Why do you think I'm confiding in you?
你仍是关键所在
You're still vital,Dean.
我们不能篡改你的命运
We weren't lying about your destiny.
只不过  细节部分会故意忽略
Just...omitted a few pertinent details.
但这给改变不了什么
But nothing's changed.
你就是命定之人
You are chosen.
你才能阻止这一切
You will stop it.
只不过  你要阻止的并非莉莉丝或是天启
Just...not Lilith or the apocalypse.
就是这样
That's all.
什么意思
Which means?
而是路西法
Lucifer.
你要阻止的是路西法
You're going to stop Lucifer.
你就是我们的小罗素·克劳
You're our own little Russell Crowe,
拥有着完美的暴戾之气
Complete with surly attitude.
当一切终结
And when it's over...
等你取得最终的胜利时
And when you've won...
你将得到
Your rewards will be...
无与伦比的回馈
Unimaginable.
平静  幸福
Peace,happiness...
再来两个处女或是七十个兔女郎
2 virgins and 70 sluts.
相信我
Trust me --
终有一天  我们再回头时定会笑看风云
One day,we'll look back on this and laugh.
跟我说说
Tell me something.
上帝都去哪儿了
Where's god in all this?
上帝
God?
上帝早离我们而去了
God has left the building.
您好啊
Howdy.
女士  这儿可是私人产业
Lady,this is private property.
你不该来这儿的
You're not supposed to be here.
但我来这儿可是为了最广大人民群众
But I'm here for mass.
当然也是为了你
And so are you.
你联系不到他的  迪恩
You can't reach him,Dean.
你已经不在服务区了
You're outside your coverage zone.
你们要对萨姆怎么着
What are you gonna do to Sam?
什么都不做
Nothing.
只是让他放手一搏罢了
He's gonna do it to himself.
到底是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
噢  对了  对了
Oh,right,right.
你不可以越界的
Got to toe the company line.
那你来这儿干嘛  卡西
Why are you here,cass?
你和我  曾患难与共多时
We've been through much together,you and I,
我只是想来说一声
And I just wanted to say,
抱歉让事情发展到了如此地步
I'm sorry it ended like this.
抱歉
"Sorry"?
那可是世界末日啊  卡西
It's armageddon,Cass.
光抱歉可不够
You need a bigger word than "sorry".
你得明白  一切早已注定
Try to understand -- this is long foretold.
这是你的
This is your...
命运
Destiny?
少给我讲你那神圣的屁话
Don't give me that "holy" crap.
命运  上帝的安排
Destiny,God's plan...
全是骗人的  你个又蠢又笨的兔崽子
It's all a bunch of lies,you poor,stupid son of a bitch!
只不过是他们让你我卖命的借口
It's just a way for your bosses to keep me and keep you in line!
你知道什么才是真的
You know what's real?
这些人  这些家庭  他们才是真的
People,families -- that's real.
你能眼睁睁看他们毁灭吗
And you're gonna watch them all burn?
有什么值得拯救的
What is so worth saving?
我在人间只看到了痛苦
I see nothing but pain here.
我看到你的内心
I see inside you.
你的罪孽  愤怒  迷惘
I see your guilt,your anger,confusion.
在天堂  一切罪孽将被饶恕
In paradise,all is forgiven.
你将得到安宁
You'll be at peace.
与萨姆和解
Even with Sam.
你安你的宁去吧
You can take your peace...
带着你洁白无暇的屁股尽情安宁
And shove it up your lily-white ass.
我宁愿选择痛苦和罪孽
'cause I'll take the pain and the guilt.
我宁愿要这样的萨姆
I'll even take Sam as is.
也不去天堂当模范婊子
It's a lot better than being some stepford bitch in paradise.
问题很简单  卡西
This is simple,Cass!
别说战士以服从为天职
No more crap about being a good soldier.
这是是非问题
There is a right and there is a wrong here,
你很清楚
And you know it.
看着我
Look at me!
你心里非常清楚
You know it!
你想过要帮我  不是么
You were gonna help me once,weren't you?
他们把你召回去的时候
You were gonna warn me about all this,
你正打算警告我
Before they dragged you back to bible camp.
帮我  现在
Help me -- now.
求你
Please.
你要我做什么
What would you have me do?
带我去找萨姆  在无法挽回之前阻止他
Get me to Sam. We can stop this before it's too late.
我带你去的话  我们会被追捕
I do that,we will all be hunted.
他们会杀了我们
We'll all be killed.
这值得我们为之
If there is anything worth dying for...
付出生命
This is it.
你个没骨气的
You spineless...
无情无义的混蛋
Soulless son of a bitch.
你怕什么死  你已经死了
What do you care about dying? You're already dead.
你走吧
We're done.
迪恩
Dean...
你走
We're done.
距圣玛丽女修道院
还有两英里
萨姆  时候到了  到底动不动手
Sam,it's time. Are we doing this or not?
让我想想
Give me a minute to think.
萨姆
Sam...
就他妈一会儿  露比
Give me a damn minute,Ruby!
快点想
Better think fast.
你有新的信息
You have one unheard message.
第一条
First unheard message.
听着  吸血的畸形
Listen to me,you bloodsucking freak.
老爸总说我要么救你要么杀了你
Dad always said I'd either have to save you or kill you.
我现在警告你
Well,I'm giving you fair warning.
我救你的时候过去了
I'm done trying to save you.
你是个怪物  萨姆  吸血鬼
You're a monster,Sam... a vampire.
你已经不是我弟弟
You're not you anymore.
没有回头路了
And there's no going back.
动手吧
Do it.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
不
No-o-o! aah!
卡西迪奥
Castiel!
能不能解释下你这是干嘛
Would you mind explaining just what the hell you're doing?
他一会儿就会回来
He won't be gone long.
我们得马上去找萨姆
We have to find Sam now.
他在哪儿
Where is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
可我知道有人知道
But I know who does.
我们得阻止他杀死莉莉丝
We have to stop him,Dean,from killing Lilith.
可是莉莉丝会打开最后一道封印
But Lilith's gonna break the final seal.
莉莉丝就是最后一道封印
Lilith is the final seal.
她一死  末日就降临
She dies,the end begins.
(复苏的路西法 卡佛·爱德伦  作)
听起来很爽
T-that sounds...moist.
怎么收费
Uh,what are your rates?
一个女孩  一小时  一千美元
We can get you one girl,one hour -- $1,000.
好吧
Okay.
给我叫20个  包夜
Then,uh,I'll take 20 girls for the whole night.
先生  您确定自己付得起吗
Um,sir,I'm not sure you can afford that.
小姐  今朝有酒今朝醉
Lady,sometimes you got to live like there's no tomorrow.
等等  不该是这样
Wait. T-t-this isn't supposed to happen.
先生
Sir?
小姐  我说的不是你
No,lady,this is definitely supposed to happen,
我们待会儿再谈
But I just got to call you back.
我
I...
别怕
Don't be afraid.
我们将拯救这个世界了
We're going to save the world.
圣玛丽  是什么  是间女子修道院吗
St. Mary's? what is it,a convent?
是的  但你们俩不该出现在那儿
Yeah,but you guys aren't supposed to be there.
这故事没你们的份儿
You're not in this story.
是的  话虽如此
Yeah,well...
但去了就自然有我们的份儿了
We're making it up as we go.
(复苏的路西法 卡佛·爱德伦  作)
噢  哥们  别再来了
Aw,man! not again!
是大天使
It's the archangel!
我来对付他  交给我
I'll hold him off! I'll hold them all off!
你去拦着萨姆
Just stop sam!
我等这一刻
I've been waiting for this...
很久了
For a very long time.
那就好好露一手给我看看吧
Then give me your best shot.
萨姆  萨姆
Sam! Sam!
萨姆
Sam!
迪恩
Dean?
你在磨蹭什么呢
What are you waiting for?!
快动手啊
Now!
萨姆  快
Sam,now!
萨姆
Sam!
萨姆  快
Sam,now!
你千辛万苦地把自己变成一个怪物
You turned yourself into a freak.
一个真真正正的怪物
A monster.
到临门一脚时却不发威了
And now you're not gonna bite?
抱歉  但这真的很可笑
I'm sorry,but that is honestly adorable.
搞什么鬼啊
What the hell?
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
露比  这怎么回事儿
Ruby,what's going on?
你搞定了
You did it.
虽然这一路走来总是磕磕碰碰的
I mean,it was a little touch-and-go there for a while,
但  最终你还是完成了
But...you did it.
什么  我  我到底完成了什么
What? what -- what did I do?
你开启了那扇门
You opened the door.
现在  他终于自由了
And now he's free at last.
他终于自由了
He's free at last.
不  不  不对
No,no,no.
不对  他  莉莉丝  我已经阻止了她
No,he -- Lilith -- I stopped her.
我已经杀了她了
I killed her!
而古书中写道
And it is written
第一个恶魔正是最后一道封印
That the first demon shall be the last seal.
正是你破除了这道封印
And you bust her open.
猜猜看即将登场的会是谁呢
Now guess who's coming to dinner.
偶滴神啊
Oh,my god.
再猜猜看
Guess again.
你无法体味这有多艰难
You don't even know how hard this was --
我根本就不把任何恶魔放在眼里
All the demons out for my head.
没人知道
No one knew.
我比那群杂碎强大多少
I was the best of those sons of bitches!
忠诚多少
The most loyal!
就连阿拉斯泰尔也不知道
Not even Alastair knew!
只有莉莉丝知道
Only Lilith!
没错  我知道你现在一定会愤怒
Yeah,I'm sure you're a little angry right now,
但是  得了吧  萨姆
But,I mean,come on,sam!
你也不得不承认
Even you have to admit --
我  就是个活孔明
I'm -- I'm awesome!
你个贱货
You bitch.
你个满口谎言的贱货
You lying bitch!
别自讨没趣了  萨姆  没用的
Don't hurt yourself,sammy. it's useless.
对付完莉莉丝就是你的极限了
You shot your payload on the boss.
那血
The blood...
你故意引我上瘾的
You poisoned me.
不对
No.
跟那血无关
It wasn't the blood.
而是你  你自己的选择问题
It was you... and your choices.
我给你不过是选项
I just gave you the options,
而享有选择自由的人可是你
And you chose the right path every time.
你根本不用我在后推波助澜的
You didn't need the feather to fly.
自然而然就水到渠成了  小飞象
You had it in you the whole time,Dumbo.
我知道这让你很难接受
I know it's hard to see it now...
但这可是期盼已久的奇迹啊
But this is a miracle so long coming.
阿撒兹勒和莉莉丝所做的一切
Everything Azazel did and Lilith did
不过都是为了能引你到这一步
Just to get you here.
你可是唯一能办到这一切的人
And you were the only one who could do it.
为什么
Why?
为  为什么是我
W-why me?
因为
Because...
因为舍你其谁呢  萨姆
Because it had to be you,Sammy.
这非你莫属
It always had to be you.
你拯救了我们
You saved us.
你让他重获自由
You set him free.
他一定会感激你的
And he's gonna be grateful.
他一定会好好补偿你的
He's gonna repay you in ways that you can't even imagine.
太迟了
You're too late.
没关系
I don't care.
对不起
I'm sorry.
萨姆  咱赶紧离开
Sammy,let's go.
迪恩
Dean...
他已经来了
He's coming.